A Guide to the Sally Waldner Bould Stan Architectural Collection, 1940-1997
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Sally Waldner Bould Stan Architectural Collection, 1940-1997
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2001-015
2.0 cu. ft.
An architect from Lafayette, California, Stan graduated from the University of California at Berkeley in 1939. She designed her first home in 1948 and retired in 1998. She worked largely for contractors, focusing on residential housing, subdivisions, and single-family dwellings. The Stan Papers include architectural drawings and sketches for single-family residences, commercial and apartment building sites. Pictures of her work are available on the VT ImageBase.
Stan, Sally Waldner Bould
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Sally Bould Stan Architectural Collection was donated to Special Collections in March 2001.
Biographical/Historical Note
Sally Bould Stan (1917 - 2008) was an architect from Lafayette, California. She graduated from the University of California at Berkeley in 1939. Her first home was designed in 1948; she retired from practicing architecture following a final job in 1998. She was the first woman to serve on the Lafayette Improvement Association, holding several roles on the community board over the course of two decades.
Scope and Content
The Stan Papers include numerous architectural drawings and sketches from 1940-1997. Sally Bould Stan worked largely for contractors, focusing on residential housing, subdivisions, and single family dwellings. Her papers include 11 commercial and apartment building sites and 42 residential plans. All plans include: living room, family room, kitchen, dining room, laundry, and 2 car garage unless otherwise noted.
History of Women in Architecture; International Archive of Women in Architecture (IAWA); Women architects -- California
Contents List
- Folder 1
  - Project 81-12. McIntyre, 521 Clayton, El Cerrito. 2 story, 4 bedroom, solar heating. 4881 sq ft.
  - Project No. 81-12. McIntyre, 521 Clayton, El Cerrito. 2 story, 4 bedroom, solar heating. 4881 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 82-1. O-Hallegren, Grove St, Sonoma. 2 bedroom, den. 2826 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 82-1A. 4 car garage below office and guest. 1279 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 82-9. Myer, Green Valley, Green Acres Ct. 4 bedroom, 2 story, extended garage, all purpose kitchen, dining room, living room. 3133 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 82-12. O-Burton, Jameson Canyon Rd., Napa Co. 3 bedroom, study, solar greenhouse, play room. 2204 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 83-3. O-Black, Pippo Place, Danville. 2 story, 3 bedroom, den, sewing. 2560 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 85-10. O-McDonald, Blue Springs Dr., Blackhawk, C.C.Co. Main bedroom, main floor, two bedroom and playroomupstairs. 3218 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 86-15. C-Mueller, 4525 Glen Cannon Rd., Green Valley. 4 bedroom, 3 car garage, playroom. 4794 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 86-18. O-Ruiz, Belle View Ct., Fairfield. 2 story, 3 bedroom, 3 car, den. 2913 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 87-1. O-Bell. 3 bedroom, 3 car decks, contra Costa Co. 4337 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 87-5. C. Holden, Victorian Lane, Danville. 3 bedroom, 3 baths, library, 1 room upstairs. 4643 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 87-6. O. Walden, 1875 Del Este St., Lafayette. 2 story, steel house, 10’’ ext. walls, 3 bedroom, 3 bath, decks. 2936 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 87-11. C. Mueller, Glen Cannon Dr., Suisan. 2 story, 4 bedroom, den, 3 car garage. 3226 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 88-2. O. Merrell, 3313 Gloria Terrace, Laf. 3 bedroom, den, 3 car, deck. 2759 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 88-3. C. Strange, Fairfield. 2 split levels, 3 car, great room, study. 4620 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 88-4. O. Dr. Gillian, Saleshun Ct., Fairfield. 2 story, 3 car, 3 bedroom, library, study, game room, exercise room, balcony. 4516 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 88-6. C. Silva, Creek Ledge Ct, Danville. 2 story, 3 car, 4 bedroom, den. 3678 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 88-7. C. Ellison, Stage Coach Dr, Laf. 2 story, 4 bedroom, den, living room, entry, 2 story ceiling. 3583 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 88-12. O. Rose, 1980 Curry Canyon Rd., Clayton. 2 story, 3 bedroom, Victorian style, Porte-cochere. 4356 sq. ft.
- Folder 2
  - Project No. 607. Glencourt at Hiller Highlands, North Hill Ct., Oakland. 3 bedroom, 2 bath, family room, view. 2363 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 620. Glencourt at Hiller Highlands, Oakland, 1964. 4 bedroom, 2 bath, O. Erwin White 2700 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 902. Sherwood Lafayette Subdivision, 62 homes, 4 bedroom, den. 2007 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 903. Sherwood Lafayette Subdivision, 3 bedroom, room over garage. 1968 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 1219. O-Dennis File, Camino Valecito, Laf. 5 bedroom, 3 car, 3 bath, and pow. 3269 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 1244. O-Adele Harlan, Bodega Bay, Sea Way and Starboard Ct. 3 bedroom, 2 bath, 2 car, ocean view.
  - Project No. 1254. O-Towner, Alamo. 2 story, 4 bedroom, guest, playroom, 3 car. 3757 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 1258. O-Meder, N. Scenic Rd., Laf. 4 bedroom. 2222 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 1668. C-Arcady, Brookwood Valley, Laf. 4 bedroom. 1668 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 1811. C-Arcady, Brookwood Valley, Laf. 4 bedroom. 1811 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 76-12. O-Cooper, South View Dr., Alamo. 3 bedroom, master bedroom suite, library. 3519 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 76-44. C-Savage, Vine Hill Way, Martinez. 2 story, 3 bedroom, 3 car. 2250 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 77-18. O-Bloodworth, Discovery Bay Blvd., C.C.Co. Floating dock, 2 story, 4 bedroom. 2606 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 77-28. C-Mueller, Gordon Valley Rd., Napa Co. 2 story, den, 3 bedroom. 3310 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 78-2. O-Bell, Discovery Bay. 4 bedroom, den, 2 story, deck. 3157 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 79-4. O-Barriskill, Rancho View Dr., Laf. House supported on poles, 3 car, 3 bedroom.
  - Project No. 79-12. C-McVicar, Tiberon. 3 story, 4 bedroom, 3 bath.O-Arson 4281 sq. ft.
- Folder 3
  - Project No. 778. Ivar Loe, Oakland. Three — 2 story units 3 bedroom. 3994 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 1046. S.K. Nielsen Hough Ave. Lafayette. Three units, 2 story, 3 bedroom. 4175 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 1101. Chase, El Monte Financial Center, corner Grove and Clayton. 2 story office, 26 parking + curb.Concord. 6288 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 1116. Mechanical Man Auto, Laundry. Pittsburg, CA.
  - Project No. 1195. Chase, 3 commercial buildings.Meadow Lane, Concord Restaurant 2604, Fast Food 815, Stop and Go Shop. 2080 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 1196. Chase, office building, Concord. 2 story 9200.1 story 4609. 13809 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 1265. Hartz, 2009 Ascot Dr. Moraga, 15 units: 6-2 bedroom townhouses. 8-1 bedroom flats.1 managers unit.
  - Project No. 75-36. D & C San Landro, Callan Ave.Apt. 16 units, park 24, 2 studios, 10-1 bedrooms, 4-1 bedroom plus den 13614 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 78-35. G & J Povda Rd. Danville. 9 townhouses 15752 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 80-6. D.L. Abbas, Inc. Clayton, CA.
  - Project No. 81-17. Mr. and Mrs. Michael O’Driscoll. Danville, CA.
  - Project No. 83-5. Lafayette United Methodist Church, Moraga Rd.Interior remodel. Combined small sanctuary and attached old school house into one larger sanctuary.
  - Project No. 87-9. Walnut Ave. United Methodist Church, Walnut Creek. Added social hall, kitchen, handicap facilities, class room and office; connected to existing sanctuary 2670 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 89-2. O. Otterson. 349 Victorian Lane, Danville. 4 bedroom, den, 3 baths. Below: garage and unfinished…1441 3973 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 89-5. O. Morgan, 2250 Hoffman Lane, Byron. 2 story, 3 car, 2 bedroom and den. Guest bedroom and bath. 2943 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 89-11. O. Fell.Edinburg Ct. Suisan. 2 story # car 3722 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 89-17. O. Dunlap Skyline Blvd. Oak. 2 story, 3 car, 4 bedroom, unfinished playroom and bath. 3578 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 90-5. C. Mueller, Glenn Canyon Rd. 2 story, 4 car garage. 3 bedroom, main floor game room, master bedroom and bath, library, etc. 6321 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 93-3. Mueller, Soscol Ave., Napa. Condo 5 plex. 2 story, 3 bedroom, 2 car garage.Each 1713 8565 sq. ft.
  - Project No. 93-7. O. Weed, 2700 Atlas Peak Rd., Napa. 3 story, Large deck over Family room. 3994 sq. ft.